# Ching-Cheong Lee

**9121-8040** 

https://github.com/machingclee

## **About Me**

Graduated from HKUST with an M.Phil degree in Mathematics, worked in both academic and nonacademic fields, with solid knowledge in both frontend and backend programming.

I am passionate about designing software architecture, with rich experience in (i) delivering services with appropriate cloud infrasturcture and (ii) building devops pipelines to facinitate team's collaboration.

# **Experience**

# **Software Engineer**

Mid of May 2023 ~ Present 1.58 Years

Wonderbricks Limited, Hong Kong

AWS. S3, Cloudfront, Lambda, EC2-loadbalancer, ECS-Fargate, Route53, API-Gateway, RDS

Frontend. Vite, React, Redux-toolkit, React-Native, React-Native-Reanimated, Next, Expo-CLI, Algolia, Socket.io-client, RevenueCat, Push Notification for iOS and Android

Backend. Express (Node.js), Spring Boot (Kotlin), JOOQ, JPA, Domain Driven Design, Prisma, Prisma-Kysely, Expo Push Notification, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Socket.io, RabbitMQ, Redis, Stripe and Stripe's Event Integration

DevOps. Github Actions, Automated: (1) Backend Deployment onto ECS; (2) Frontend Deployment onto S3 and Cloudfront; (3) Deployment of Lambda functions

Web Application (Mid-05/2023 to Mid-09/2023)

#### Frontend.

· Revamp and maintain an existing React project in Typescript

#### Backend.

· Maintain existing Spring Boot project in Java, build APIs by iBatis and mongo-java-driver

## Mobile Application (Mid-09/2023 to Present)

### Frontend.

- Developed a realtime text-messaging and LLM based project from scratch by React-Native and EXPO
- · Created custom interactive components by React-Native-Reanimated
- Integrated RevenueCat in frontend

### Backend and Infrastructure.

### Database (PostgreSQL + MongoDB).

- Conducted schema migration via Prisma for dev and non-dev environments
- Managed user accounts by granting appropriate privileges in PostgreSQL database
- Used both PostgreSQL for business-centric data and MongoDB for complex json object resulted from LLM model
- Designed and adjusted tables in PostgreSQL to fulfll ever-changing requirements

## Backend Project 1 (Nodejs Express, serving mobile and web applications).

- Decided to use query builder (Prisma-Kysely) instead of any existing ORMs, making the application readily maintainable by anyone who knows basic SQL
- Designed middleware to let user send text, audio, images via REST apis and broadcast the message via socket.io
- Developed Push notification system for ios and android
- Introduced the concept of domain objects, make clear distinction between a repository and a DAO
- Implemented an ApplicationEventPublisher (for DDD) with decorators: @listener, @order, @nextEvent. Listeners are registered with the help of reflect-metadata.

## Backend Project 2, 3 (Kotlin Spring Boot, 1 serving mobile and 1 serving payment).

- Integrated with Stripe and RevenueCat for purchasing in-app resources in our applications, integration includes:
  - □ Subscribe, upgrade, downgrade and cancel the monthly plans
  - □ Distribute purchased in-app resources to team members

## **Blog**

https://machingclee.github.io/blog

### Portfolio

https://machingclee.github.io/portfolio

### Education

# MicroMaster in A.I. and Programming

Tecky Academy
Mar 2019 ~ June 2019

#### M.Phil. in Mathematics

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology Sep 2012 ~ Aug 2014

# **B.Sc. in Mathematics**Pure Math Option, **1st Class Honor**

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology Sep 2009 ~ June 2012

## Skills

### Source Control

Git

#### Deployment

Docker, Github Actions

## Cloud (AWS)

Security Group, Target Group, Load Balancer, ECS Fargate, Route53, S3, CloudFront, Lambda Functions, API-Gateway, RDS, SQS

## Typescript

React, React-Native, Redux, Redux-Toolkit, React-Query, Next.js, Electron.js, Electron with Next.js, Node.js, Express.js, Socket.io, Twilio.js, Knex.js, Mongoose.js, Prisma.js, Prisma-Kysely.js

### Kotlin

Spring Boot, JPA, JOOQ, Domain Driven Design, JUnit 5

### Golang

Gin, Goose, Sqlc, Azure-sdk for Voice, Go-Jet

## Python

Tensorflow v2, PyTorch, Pandas, Flask, ONNX, Openpyxl, Boto3, Mongoengine, Selenium, Conda

### C++

CMake Ecosystem, Libtorch, OpenCV, ImGui for Desktop App

### C#

Windows Presentation Foundation

## Database Query & Management

PostgreSQL, MongoDB

- □ Studied all kinds of stripe events and designed metadatas in Stripe operations, enabled the backend to make persistence changes in database according to correct events and metadatas
- Designed test cases via JUnit5 to mimic the subscription processes
- Built repository layer using JPA which returns AbstractAggregateRoot; Reverse
  engineered existing database into @Entity classes by JOOQ (surgery needed)
- Made use of Coroutines and context Dispatchers.IO intensively for IO tasks via DeferredResult which is available from spring 3.2 onwards
- Designed AOPs to track program excution flows and to store domain events because database history is very important to the payment service

### System Design.

- Queuing. Used RabbitMQ to (i) Rate limit api which has a limit of 100 concurrent calls (azure openai service); (ii) Delay actions by staling messages into DeadLetter Queue
- Inapp Notification. Created a table to store notification in granular level, and designed API to enable the frontend to display notification such as (i) New messages in a channel; (ii) New channels to join; (iii) Number of Unread Messages in a chat room
- **Payment.** Designed table to allow users to subscribe, upgrade, downgrade and cancel plans for the extra usage limit in our app

## **AWS Cloud Solution**

- Deployed node.js and spring boot application onto ECS
- Created Scheduled Task running in container via ECS to backup PostgreSQL and MongoDB database regularly at the same time
- Shared knowledge how to config load-balancer to detect special header in order for my teammates to route requests to a special backend (e.g., for apple tester in iOS app)
- Developed Lambda functions in various use cases such as (i) LLM Application in
  Python; (ii) file generation and google authentications in Node.js; and (iii) ordinary
  snap-started spring boot application in Kotlin
- Developed Lambda functions to execute web application in docker image, both in python and nodejs when unzipped file size inevitably exceeds 250MB. e.g.,
  - □ Used packages (i) react, (ii) react-pdf and (iii) sharp for pdf-file generation
  - □ Used Langchain with CPU-inference model such as fasttext (with huge weight file)

### DevOps / CICD via Github Actions

- Created automated deployment workflows for frontend and backend via github actions.
   Automations include:
  - □ Deployment of containerized node.js and spring boot application using AWS ECS Fargate via the following steps
    - 1. Push to image registry
    - 2. Update task defintion
    - 3. Instruct ECS Serivce to use the updated task
  - □ Deployment of all frontend projects onto S3 and cache-invalidation in AWS Cloudfront
  - □ Deployment of Lambda functions
- Created Docker Action written in python to let teammates download cloudwatch logs from various log-group and from custom start-time (via workflow\_dispatch options), with the log file being downloadable as an artifact

## iOS Deployment to AppStore with EXPO.

- · Handled App Submissions and Rejections via TestFlight
- Created OTA Update to patch the application
- Managed everything above with 3 stages (DEV, UAT, PROD)

# **AI Engineer**

15 Aug 2022 ~ April 2023 8.4 Months

Eye Catching Limited, Hong Kong

Python. PyTorch

Typescript. Tensorflow, Onnx

C++. Libtorch, Imgui, CMake Ecosystem

- Maintained angular project
- · Studied eye-tracing related algorithm

Rus

Implementation of Elliptic Curve Digital Signature Algorithm, Code Explanation and Implementation

Data Streaming/Monitoring

Kafka with Debezium

Message Broker

RabbitMQ, AWS SQS

Art

Photoshop CC, 3DS Max, Saola Animate (HTML5 Game), 2D Game Character Design

### Art Portfolio

https://www.artstation.com/checkercc

- Studied and deployed machine leanning algorithm in web-app and desktop-app
- Completely translated a BlazeFace model in python into the same model in libtorch of C++ for GUI application
- Implemented methods to ensure weights in pytorch model can be used in libtorch model
- Studied CMake and developed software to combine libtorch model and imgui application

# Senior Software Developer

Sep 2021 ~ July 2022 10.9 Months

RaSpect Intelligence Inspection Limited, Hong Kong

Python. Selenium, Boto3, Mongoengine, gRPC, PyTorch, Tensorflow

Annotation. CVAT, COCO-Annotator

Al-General. Data Annotation, DataLoader with Various Data Augmentations, Model Training

for Rust Detection, Model Training for Crack Detection

Al-Models. GAN for Producing Synthetic Data, Faster RCNN from Scratch and its Modifica-

tion, Single Stage Headless Face Detector into Rust Detector

Web Related

- · Maintained React Next project
- Implemented data scrapping for house transactions records
- Automated the process of tracking latest rtk-data from official geodetic website and data-processing pipeline using selenium and pywinauto

## **Object Detection Related**

- Text Detection. Managed to run an open-sourced text detection (EAST) to facilitate signboard defect classification
- Crack Detection. Helped implement detection model for crack and spalling
- **Rust Detection**. Implemented two solutions: (i) Text removal, then classification pipeline; and (ii) direct object detection model using faster rcnn

## Image Generation/Inpainting

- **DefectGAN.** Implemented image-generation model following this paper that generates synthetic data on cracks and spallings for training defect detection models on facades
- Text Removal. Experimented with existing algorithms like various GAN or image-inpainting method in pytorch. Finally I follow this paper to obtain a text eraser with satisfactory performance

# Software Engineer

Aug 2020 ~ Mid-Aug 2021 <sup>1.03 Years</sup>

EAB Systems (Hong Kong) Limited, Hong Kong

Typescript. React, Redux, React-Native, Express, Mongoose, Sendgrid, Twilio, socket.io Python. Pandas, Tensorflow v2

## Web Application

- Built video conferencing frontend and backend application in React, Twilio and express
- Built CMS system that lets users create their own single page application

## Machine Learning Related

- Built CSV Importer (together with an express layer and a Flask layer) that can parse a csv/excel file and perform:
  - □ **Data Classification.** Classified column based on existing data using LSTM model with two dense layers and finally a softmax (sample code)
  - □ **Auto Date-reformatting.** Based on machine learning model (transformer in NLP), translated all common form of date into YYYY-MM-DD format (sample code)

## eLearningPro, Hong Kong

Javascript. React

Python. tkinter, pyinstaller

Art. Adobe Premiere, Adobe Photoshop, Saola Animate (CSS Animation)

- Create HTML5 Games, maintain web pages and construct React frontend application
- Created a python GUI project for text extraction from an image (a work necessary to translate old fresh game into html5 game, <u>detail</u>)

## **2D Game Artist**

Jan 2018 - Dec 2018 11 Months

深圳瘋点子科技有限公司, Sheng Zheng

ullet Responsible for constructing 3d accessories, creating environment art and character design. Game that I worked on  $\underline{\mathrm{link}}$ 

## Senior Research Assistant

Mar 2015 - Oct 2015 <sup>6.9 Months</sup>

Department of Mathematics, Hong Kong Baptist University, Hong Kong

• Study HJB equations arised in specific financial games

## **Research Assistant**

Sep 2014 - Feb 2015 6 Months

Department of Mathematics, Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong

• Study the properties of viscosity solution of HJB equations

# **Teaching Assistant**

Sep 2012 - June 2014 1.82 Years

Department of Mathematics, Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, Hong Kong

• Fulfill teaching duty as required in obtaining studentship in the course of M.Phil study. Subjects include: [1] Calculus II, [2] Linear Algebra, [3] Mathmatical Analysis, [4] Real Analysis.